go a statically typed compiled language often described as c for the 21st
go 一种静态类型的编译语言，通常被描述为 21
century it's a popular choice for high-performance server-side
世纪的 c，它是高性能服务器端
applications and is the language that built tools like docker cockroachdb and
应用程序的流行选择，并且是构建 docker cockroachdb 和
d-graph it was created at google in 2007 by legends who really know their stuff
d-graph 等工具的语言，它是 2007 年在谷歌由传奇人物创建的 真正了解他们的东西，
like ken thompson the inventor of the b and c programming languages version 1.0
比如 ken thompson，b和 c 编程语言的发明者 1.0 版
was released as open source software in 2012. it was designed for simplicity and
于 2012 年作为开源软件发布。它的设计是为了简单和
efficiency and that's why we call it go and not go lang the source code is
高效，这就是为什么我们称它为 go而不是 go lang 源代码被
compiled down to machine code which means it generally outperforms
编译 直到机器代码，这意味着它通常优于
interpreted languages but it's famous for its extremely fast compile times
解释型语言，但它以依赖分析的创新实现极快的编译时间而闻名
made possible by innovations to dependency analysis and even though it's
，即使它是
a statically typed language it performs type inference to deliver a syntax that
一种静态类型语言，它也会执行类型推断以提供
is very concise and practical it also has a package and module system making
非常简洁实用的语法还有一个包和模块系统，
it easy to import and export code between projects to get started install
可以轻松地在项目之间导入和导出代码以开始安装 l
go and then open an empty directory on your system create a file ending in go
go 然后在你的系统上打开一个空目录创建一个以 go 结尾的文件
then add package main at the top to create a standalone executable then
然后在顶部添加 package main 以创建一个独立的可执行文件然后
declare a main function which is where your program will start executing go has
声明一个 main 函数，这是你的程序将开始执行的地方 go 有
a standard library of core packages to handle common requirements like math
一个标准的核心包库 要通过导入 fmt 来处理数学网络或格式化 io 等常见需求，
networking or formatted io by importing fmt we can print a line to the standard
我们可以在标准输出中打印一行，
output then run the go build command and it quickly compiles the source code and
然后运行 go build 命令，它会快速将源代码和依赖
dependencies into an executable binary when it comes to dependencies we can
项编译成可执行的二进制文件，当涉及到依赖项时，我们还可
also link to remote packages on github run go mod init from the command line
以链接 到 github 上的远程包从命令行运行 go mod init
and that creates a go module file that enables dependency tracking
并创建一个启用依赖跟踪的 go 模块文件，
syntactically go is like a concise version of c or c plus plus declare a
语法上 go 就像一个简洁版本的 c 或 c plus 声明一个
variable with the var keyword followed by its name and type and initialize it
变量，其中 var 关键字后跟其名称和类型 并
with a value or you might use the short assignment syntax to replace var and let
用一个值初始化它，或者您可以使用短赋值语法替换 var 并
go automatically infer the type and you can define multiple variables from a
自动推断类型，您可以定义 mu  ltiple variables from a
single line go has all the other features you would expect in a
single line go具有您在编程语言中所期望的所有其他功能，
programming language like arrays maps loops and control flow but also allows
例如数组映射循环和控制流，但还允许
you to store the memory address of a value using pointers while disallowing
您使用指针存储值的内存地址，同时不允许
pointer arithmetic which often leads to dangerous and unpredictable behavior in
指针运算，这通常会导致危险和 不可预知的行为
addition it supports concurrency with go routines which are functions that can
此外它还支持与 go例程的并发性，这些函数可以
run at the same time as other functions by utilizing multiple threads on a cpu
通过利用 cpu 上的多个线程与其他函数同时运行
this has been go in 100 seconds hit the like button if you want to see more
如果您想查看更多短视频，请在 100 秒内完成点击喜欢按钮
short videos like this and check out the full article to write your first 100
这个并查看完整的文章来写你的前 100
lines of go on fireship io thanks for watching and i will see you in the next
行 on fireship io 感谢收看，我会在下一篇见到你
one